Alex Cline

New Orleans, Louisiana, 70116 | 504-493-8038 | <u>alexanderrcline@gmail.com</u> <u>github.com/revarcline</u> | <u>buckar.ooo</u> | <u>linkedin.com/in/alexandercline/</u>

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and Elixir/Phoenix programming. Possesses strong skills in team-building and peer education that help build productivity and co-operation. Strong self-taught experience with Linux and proficiency in CLI-based workflows on remote systems. Currently transitioning from the hospitality industry into software engineering.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL (especially postgres), Javascript, React, Elixir, Phoenix, Python, bash/zsh, Linux (esp. Ubuntu/Debian and Arch), systemd, Lua, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

cellarmonster - Github | Demo

Wine cellar inventory system for restaurants and hotels in React and Rails

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Live updating inventory totals from orders along with robust wine attribute management
- Deployed React interface with Netlify and Rails API on Heroku dyno
- Implemented robust text search across all Rails records with pg_search
- Fully written using functional components and React Hooks along with Redux to store state

exquisite - Github | Demo

Online version of surrealist parlor game "The Exquisite Corpse" in Javascript and Rails

- Developed functions to generate Bootstrap grid in Javascript frontend
- Passed JSON data between JS frontend and Rails backend
- Deployed Single-page application on Netlify and Rails API on Heroku
- Used nested form capabilities of Rails to easily create new records

petrescue - Github | Demo

Rails application to browse pets available for adoption from rescues and shelters

- Implemented and customized Bootstrap styling in Rails templates
- Used Google OAuth to create and log in user accounts alongside devise
- Created model-based appointment system using ActiveRecord's powerful time and date tools
- Deployed with Heroku and cloudinary for image upload and display

EXPERIENCE

Tujague's RestaurantServer

New Orleans, LA
2019 - 2020

- Worked floor and banquet events as server and bartender, coordinating teammates for events
- Accomplished high level of food, beverage, and wine sales in fast-paced customer-facing setting

Salon by Sucré
New Orleans, LA
Server/Bartender
2018 - 2019

- Worked floor, bar, and banquet events at brunch-only restaurant concept in tight-knit team environment
- Helped to develop rigorous in-house cocktail and wine education program for staff, increasing sales

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Online

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 12/2020 - 06/2021

New College of Florida

Bachelor of Arts, History

Sarasota, Florida

01/2011